# **Gabriel Pivaro**

gfp.1@hotmail.com | Phone: 832-57-6542 | Houston, Tx 77012

LinkedIn: <a href="linkedin.com/in/gabriel-pivaro">linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/gabriel-pivaro</a> | Github: <a href="github.com/gpivaro">github.com/gpivaro</a> | Website: <a href="gpivaro.com">gpivaro.com</a> | Google Scholar (Academic Research Papers): <a href="scholar.google.com/citations?user=410r\_NUAAAAJ">scholar.google.com/citations?user=410r\_NUAAAAJ</a>

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software developer with a Bachelor's in Math and Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering. Received certification in data analytics from Rice University with advanced skills in Python, MATLAB, SQL implementation and web development. Proven records of applying statistical analysis and predictive modeling to generate simulations to support academic research and business analysis. Excellent written, oral communication, and presentation skills. Enthusiastic to solve complex problems that require mathematical modeling, hardware integration and full-stack web development applications.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Plotly, D3.js, Chart.js, Leafleat.js
- Backend: MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Python Flask/Django, Linux bash and cloud technologies (AWS)
- Statistical Analysis: scikit-learn, Pandas, TensorFlow, Excel, MATLAB, MATHEMATICA, STATISTICA
- Research: Authored over 15 research papers with statistical analyzes and Monte Carlo simulation
- Teaching: Created student material and instructed Statistics undergraduate course and Telecom courses
- Hardware: RaspberryPi automation hobbyist, Linux servers (Debian, Ubuntu), Software Defined Radio (SDR)

#### **PROJECTS**

**Earthquakes Sentinel** - gpivaro.github.io/leaflet-challenge/ | github.com/gpivaro/leaflet-challenge

Interactive web application that displays all the earthquakes of the last 7 days from the USGS

- Designed a web app that allows users to visualize and interact with data about earthquakes and tectonic plates.
- Tools used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Global Air Traffic Live Tracker - gpivaro.github.io/Project 2 | gpivaro.com/airtraffic/

Full-stack web app that display live air traffic information about air crafts and airports all over the world

- Led a team of four in creating a full-stack web app to keep track of live air traffic data
- Tools used: MySQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Global Air Traffic Live Tracker - gpivaro.github.io/Project\_3 | find-your-dream-home.herokuapp.com/

Full-stack web app that integrates Machine Learning K-means techniques to suggest real estate for users

- Designed a web app using Python-Flask to scrap real estate on the market and cluster it by price range and location saving it to a SQL database. The frontend allows user classification based on previous user's choices.
- Tools used: MySQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Heroku server

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Technology Support Specialist, Woodforest National Bank, Houston, Tx

08/2020 - present

- Developed an Excel VBA macro to automate tasks that reduced the time on this task in over 1h/day/operator
- Achieved a resolution rate higher than 97% in IT related problems (standard is 85%)

Wireless Communication Researcher, National Institute of Telecommunications, Brazil

06/2016 – 05/2018

Received substantial monetary funds for research projects by writing request for proposal projects

Visiting Scholar at Electrical and Computational Engineering, Rice University, Houston, Tx

03/2015 - 03/2016

Co-authored scientific paper published in world-class scientific journal

#### **EDUCATION**

Data Analytics & Visualization Boot Camp | Rice University, Houston, Tx Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering | State University of Campinas, Brazil Bachelor's degree in Mathematics | Sao Paulo State University, Brazil

01/2021